#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ sankarayadavalli (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Java

Core Java

Struts2

### Languages

English (Full Professional)
Hindi (Professional Working)
Telugu (Full Professional)

# Sankara Yadavalli

Associate Director at Verizon

Edison, New Jersey, United States

## Summary

A diversely skilled Applications Development Technical Lead Programmer/Architect and having a strong background and experience in designing and developing of software applications, Experienced in building complex J2EE applications, sophisticated products.

My key concern is the successful delivery of the project. My key skills are problem discovery, solving and being able to deliver quality work efficiently.

Specialties: Solution Architect/Sr. Java Developer

## Experience

Verizon

9 years

**Associate Director** 

August 2022 - Present (9 months)

Sr. Mgr IT Sys Engineer

June 2019 - August 2022 (3 years 3 months)

Piscataway, New Jersey

Mgr IT Sys Eng

May 2017 - June 2019 (2 years 2 months)

Piscataway, NJ

Information Technology Solutions Architect May 2014 - May 2017 (3 years 1 month)

Piscataway, NJ

I work for Verizon.

Barclays Investment Bank Senior Technical Lead June 2011 - May 2014 (3 years) New York, NY

I worked for Risk Finance Data Warehouse application implemented multiple components Direct Sourcing Services, Event Manager and Feed Generator in Core Java, Multi threading, Spring, iBatis, JMS-MQ, Coherence, Hibernate JPA and Oracle.

Verizon Wireless

Sr. Programmer Analyst April 2009 - June 2011 (2 years 3 months)

Worked on Sync and Connect Project and implemented it in J2EE architecture, Sun Messaging Server, IMAP Web Sphere Application Server and eXtreme Scale.

Keane Inc., Sr. Systems Analyst

May 2006 - April 2009 (3 years)

New York, NY

I worked at Goldman Sachs as a Consultant, New York. Designed and implemented Syndicate Sub Ledger and supported Investment Banking, Asset Management, Fund Account valuation and Reporting, Fund Investments & processing applications.

Malvi Systems LLC

Sr. Programmer Analyst
October 2004 - May 2006 (1 year 8 months)

Pricenton Jct, NJ

I worked as a Sr. Programmer Analyst and handled NGTS in Liberty Travels, Mahwah, NJ and ATOMS in Administrative of Courts, Trenton. Both the projects worked on J2EE platform with Struts and EJB2.0 implementation.

**HTC Global Services** 

**Project Leader** 

November 2002 - September 2004 (1 year 11 months)

I have implemented multiple projects using the J2EE architecture, Struts and Oracle DB. I have lead the Work Flow Management, eGrams.

Bridgelogix

Sr. Java Developer

October 2001 - November 2002 (1 year 2 months)

Worked as a Sr. Java Developer and helped to customize some of the Baan Products in Java.

Rao Consultants Inc

Java Developer

October 2000 - October 2001 (1 year 1 month)

Worked as a Java Consultant and implemented multi projects in J2EE Architecture

Modelsoft

Java Developer

December 1998 - October 2000 (1 year 11 months)

Worked in Bank Automation project implemented using the Swing, Core Java and Oracle DB.

## Education

Acharya Nagarjuna University

MCA, Masters in Computers · (1996 - 1999)

Acharya Nagarjuna University

1996, Bachelors in Computers · (1993 - 1996)